iucn.org 2018-11-01

# Privacy Policy | IUCN

IUCN, International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources ("IUCN" or “We” or “Us”) is committed to protecting your privacy and would like to ensure that you get information, content and experiences that matter to you the most.

This Privacy Policy applies to all persons who access the IUCN website “www.iucn.org”, and all associated subdomains, online services and mobile applications (collectively, the “Website”).

## Information collected from you

IUCN may collect personal information from its Member representatives, Councillors, Commission Members, Partners, Donors, Visitors, Volunteers, Congress participants, IUCN Providers, Newsletter subscribers and other contacts.

When you visit the Website, for example when you [subscribe to a newsletter](https://www.iucn.org/newsletters), comment on a blog or [choose to donate](https://www.iucn.org/donate) to IUCN, IUCN may collect your personal information such as designation, name, gender, position, address, telephone number, mobile number, email address, date of birth.

## Information use

### Legitimate purposes

IUCN uses your personal information for legitimate purposes determined when the personal information is collected such as

  * when you apply to become an IUCN member;
  * when you subscribe to IUCN newsletters or publications;
  * when you donate to the work of IUCN;
  * to provide you with specific information, support or other requested services;
  * to communicate with you about a meeting, conference or event;
  * to assist in your participation in IUCN activities;
  * to communicate with IUCN partners;
  * to engage with third party service providers;
  * to get feedback or input from you;
  * to conduct surveys about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered;
  * for any other interactions that you may have with IUCN.

### Consent

IUCN will ask for your consent prior to using your personal information where consent is considered to be the appropriate legal basis of processing.

### Mailing lists

You will not be placed on any mailing list that you do not opt-in to.

### Sharing information with others and transferring personal information

IUCN may provide your personal information to other IUCN offices in other regions, members and partners for legitimate business purposes and on a need-to-know basis in compliance with IUCN Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

IUCN may transfer your personal information to service providers who assist us in administering the Website. These service providers are bound by contractual agreements to keep your information private and secure.

Please note that whenever your personal information is transferred to processors located in countries which do not provide an adequate level of personal data protection, IUCN ensures that appropriate measures are implemented according to the applicable national and international legislation relating to data protection.

### Commercial use

IUCN does not sell, rent or lease your personal information to third parties nor does not make commercial use of personal information. In case IUCN needs to use your personal information for commercial purposes in the scope of its mission, IUCN will ask for your express consent prior to any such usage.

### Special categories of data

IUCN will not collect or process any special category of personal information relating to you such as information revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data for uniquely identifying a natural person, health, sex life or sexual orientation.

### Compliance with our legal obligations

IUCN may disclose your personal information without your consent where required to do so by law or in good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) comply with legal process; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of IUCN; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Website, or the public.

## Your rights

You can ask to access, rectify or delete the personal information you have provided to IUCN. You may also request to be informed how your personal information is being processed, object to further processing or request restriction of processing.

Where applicable, you may also request to receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. In such cases, IUCN reserves the right to request a reasonable fee in order to deal with the request.

Such requests should be submitted using this [online form](https://portals.iucn.org/dataprotection/requestform).

## Storage duration and how to control your personal information

IUCN keeps personal information for as long as it is necessary to perform its activities and as is required by applicable law. You may withdraw your consent at any time. If you withdraw your consent or ask that your personal information be deleted, IUCN will disable or delete the information except where there exists another legal basis of processing such as:

  * to comply with a legal obligation;
  * to comply with a contractual obligation;
  * for the legitimate interest of IUCN; or
  * in the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in IUCN through its mandate or Statutes.

If you have subscribed to an IUCN newsletter you may ask not to continue to receive the newsletter by unsubscribing from the newsletter(s).

If you have a user account, you may control your personal information by accessing the information through the account.

Alternatively, you may submit your request using this [online form](https://portals.iucn.org/dataprotection/requestform).

## Links to other sites

The Website may contain links to other external websites for your convenience and should not be construed as constituting any endorsement or approval of the external websites’ content. We take reasonable care in linking external websites but have no direct control over their content or the changes that may occur to the content on those websites.

If you access other external websites using the links provided, the operators of those websites may collect personal information from you that will be used by them in accordance with their own privacy policies. IUCN is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such websites. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of any other websites that you visit, including external websites linked from the Website.

## Use of cookies

We use cookies on the Website for a number of purposes. Cookies help us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the Website, and also allow us to improve it. By continuing to browse the Website, you are agreeing to the use of cookies. The Website is using the following cookies:

**Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of the Website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of the Website.

**Analytical/performance cookies**. These are cookies that allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors using the Website and to see how visitors move around the Website. This helps us to improve the way the Website works, for example, by ensuring that you find what they are looking for easily.

**Functionality cookies**. These are cookies used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**First-party (IT Governance Ltd) cookies.** We use some cookies that are essential for the Website to operate correctly. These cookies, none of which capture personal information, are as follows:

  * **Visitor ID** – this cookie is a numeric value that identifies unique visitors and provides coherence and consistency to a site visit;
  * **Page ID** – this cookie identifies the page you are on;
  * **Session ID** – this cookie identifies your website session.

**Third-party cookies.** The Website may use several types of third-party cookie which include but are not limited to:

  * **Google Analytics** – we use Google Analytics to collect data about the Website usage. This data does not include personal information. You can view the Google Privacy Policy here: www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
  * **AddThis** – the AddThis cookie is used when you use the ShareThis service on the Website to share a link with LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, etc. You can read the AddThis Privacy Policy here: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy>.
  * **YouTube** – The Website integrates components of YouTube. When you view a video on IUCN website, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of the Website was visited by you. If you are also logged in your YouTube account, this information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to your respective YouTube account as well. Further information about YouTube privacy policy may be obtained here:  <https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines.>

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the Website.

## Sharing on social networks

From time to time, IUCN may use social media platforms such as Facebook and Twitter to deliver targeted communications to accounts which have given consent to be contacted by advertisers. IUCN does not obtain or store this personal information at any time. To change your settings on these services, please refer to the privacy settings section of the platform.

## Security of your personal information

IUCN is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. Any personal information provided to IUCN by you is handled with due care and security, and will not be used in ways other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, or in any site/area-specific policies, or in ways to which you have not explicitly consented.

IUCN employs a range of technologies and security measures to protect the information maintained on IUCN systems from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction.

However, since the internet is not an entirely secure environment, IUCN cannot ensure nor guarantee the security of any information that you may transmit to the Website. There is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of IUCN’s physical, technical or managerial safeguards. In the case of a data breach IUCN will inform the relevant authorities and all potentially impacted users.

All IUCN employees (and IUCN external service providers) who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal information are obliged to respect the confidentiality of all such personal information and abide by applicable data protection principles.

IUCN partners’ sites or the sites found by the search may request from you your user Id, password and/or any sensitive personal information. It is your responsibility to check in each specific case if the pages secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

## How to contact IUCN

IUCN is the data controller for personal information collected through means stated in this Privacy Policy. To find IUCN’s address and offices in other regions, see: <https://www.iucn.org/contact>.

Requests regarding your rights and any other general questions should be sent using this [online form](https://portals.iucn.org/dataprotection/requestform).

## Effective date and modifications

This Privacy Policy is effective from 1 June 2018. IUCN may modify or change this Privacy Policy from time to time, at any time without notice to you, by posting such changes on the Website. IUCN encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how IUCN collects and uses your personal information as well as be informed of your rights.

Thank you for visiting [www.iucn.org ](https://www.iucn.org/)
